Carlos Henrique Rocha Gabriel

Lisbon - Portugal

Phone: +351 934235485

E-mail: chrochagabriel@icloud.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/carlos-henrique-rocha-gabriel





Goal

Mobile Developer

Profile

I have a Postgraduate degree in Software Architecture, a Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare, a Bachelor's degree in information systems, an Electromechanical Technician. I have more than 11 years of professional experience. I have experience and capacity for the roles of Mobile Developer, Fullstack Developer, Tech Lead, Backend Developer, Software Engineer, always working as a team with excellence and strong leadership.

I developed interest in the area of development of information systems through the use of Excel. From this experience I went to get more information about the development area and I went through several technologies like Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, Java Script, C #.

All this way has consolidated a career of Developer Full Stack (who loves front end, and knows the importance of UI/UX in the system) and Mobile Developer multi platform development expert with Xamarin throughout its application life cycle.

Education | Graduation | Qualification

Master of Artificial Intelligence in Health – Cemp Education – Studying

Postgraduate Distributed Software Architecture – Pontifical Catholic University – 2019

Bachelor's degree in information system – University Center of Southern – 2017

Electromechanical Technician - CEFET-MG - 2007

English Advanced | Portuguese Fluent

Experience

Xpand-It – Dec 2021 — Present

Role: Mobile Senior Developer

Azure Administrator | Scrum Master | Sitecore Developer | Microservice Architecture | Senior FullStack Developer | Support team junior development.

Bee Engineering – May 2021 — Nov 2021

Role: Xamarin Developer

Development of new social network using Xamarin.Android | C#, Git, Xamarin.Android, AppCenter | Whiz – Apps no Google Play.

Glic - Quasar – Jan 2018 — Jun 2022

Role: Mobile Architect – Freelancer

Application development for the health sector (diabetes) | Technical analysis of new features | Planning and design of new features | Legacy maintenance | Mobile application architecture | Mobile application devops (iOS/android) | Agile practices | C#, Xamarin.Forms, Xamarin.iOS, Xamarin.Android, AppCenter, Bitbucket, GIT, Devops, Agile.

Qualitab - Oct 2019 — Nov 2021

Role: Mobile Architect – Freelancer

Development of mobile applications with Flutter | Definition of mobile applications architecture with Flutter | Maintenance on mobile applications with Flutter | Maintenance in mobile applications with Cordova | Definition of devops strategies for mobile applications | Implementing devops for mobile applications | Flutter, Cordova, Git, GitLab, Devops(fastlane), Mobile Architecture.

SGA Tecnologia Inteligente – Jun 2020 — May 2021

Role: Tech Lead, Developer Specialist

Techedge Brasil – Feb 2020 — Jun 2020

Role: Senior Software Engineer

FieldCorp – Jul 2019 — Feb 2020 Role: Senior Developer Analyst

Reply – Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

Role: Software architect

Grupo Mult (MRV) – Aug 2017 — Aug 2018

Role: Senior Analyst Xamarin

Cotemig College – Jan 2018 — Feb 2018

Role: Teacher

Zarb Solutions – Mar 2017 — Aug 2017

Role: Teacher

Squadra Tecnologia – Jan 2017 — Jun 2017

Role: Senior Analyst Developer

Skills | Courses | Certificates

Skills: TypeScript | Angular | Node.js | Bootstrap | Docker | jQuery | HTML & CSS | SQL | ASP.NET Core | Angular 2+ | ASP.NET MVC | JavaScript | Android Development | iOS Development | DevOps | Microsoft Azure | Java | HTML5 | HTML | MySQL | Git | Xamarin | C# | Oracle | Sql Server | Bootstrap 4 | Enterprise Architecture | Architectural Design | backend Development | Front-End Development | Flutter | jQuery | Sitecore Developer.

Competencies

Ability to act as Mobile Developer, Fullstack Developer, Tech Lead, Backend Developer, Software Engineer.

Development and maintenance of Xamarin/MAUI/Flutter mobile applications | Development and support of integrations | Delivery of backlog tasks to active projects | Knowledge of agile scrum | Development and maintenance of high-performance and scalable mobile applications | Leadership of the architecture and design of technical solutions to ensure efficiency, scalability and code reuse.

Implementing and maintaining clean, high-quality code standards | Identifying and resolving performance, security and scalability issues in existing applications | Providing guidance and technical support | Testing and deployment in software development | Development of systems solutions.

Software and application development, carrying out requirements analysis, defining product architecture, unit and functional testing | Application of best practices for managing the data environment and its integration.

Additional Information

Soft skills: Educated | Empathetic | Leadership | Initiative | Direct.